Christopher Salgado

Github: github.com/cgado12 | **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/csgado **Website:** csalgado.me | **Email:** csgado@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with experience building and testing web apps built in JavaScript and Go. Some examples include writing custom form components to handle complicated requirements, writing graphql resolvers, mutations, and queries to setup new web page capabilities, setting up a graph visualization foundation to see the benefit of graph analysis, or pairing up with other developers to solve whatever is in our way. My experience is across the stack, and I enjoy using it.

EDUCATION

University of South Florida

Tampa, FL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2014 - May 2018

EXPERIENCE

Novetta

Full Stack Developer (Clearance: Active TS)

July 2019 - Current

- Participate in all levels of the tech stack to to build an enterprise grade software system solution
- Collaborate in an agile lifecycle to focus on building the front end and middle tier applications
- Brought various features from concept to implementation, including direction given "on-the-fly"
- Shared and documented use case examples while researching best technologies to build product

ISPA Technology | Novetta

Full Stack Developer

Mar 2018 - July 2019

- Implement features and bug fixes across the full stack of a growing in-production application
- Discuss application technical tradeoffs for enhancing the design and ease of growth
- Lead UI design and ensure accurate documentation used to instruct and bring on new team members

University of South Florida

Undergraduate Researcher (Java, Python)

Aug 2017 - May 2018

- Study the distinction of topological data analysis and traditional data analysis on 1 dimensional signals
- Design and implement various data filtering techniques on real-world datasets
- Implement custom visualizations showing the results collected using a framework called Processing

PROJECTS

Rhea: Intermittent Fasting Tracker

Feb 2020 - Current

- Implementing a fasting tracker to learn more about mobile development and AWS services
- Practice utilizing patterns involving app context, authentication, local storage, and persistent storage
- Defining milestones to work toward building a planned MVP mobile application

TechFrontier: Simple & Direct News App

July 2019

- News application built with expo that pulls current technology headlines from news API
- Defined application stage via issue tracking and learned a lot about how to use react-native

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript/ Typescript, Go, Java, Python

Libraries/Tools: React, React-native, node, Sketch, AWS, Docker, pgAdmin

Databases: Postgres, graphql